# Khoa Pham

Senior Application Developer

## Profile

I'm a co-founder and Director of Technology at Romance.

I have background of computer science and many years of experience with web application to develop great user experience products for clients.

I love experimenting with new technologies and architecting applications. My current interests: ThreeJS, Canvas Animation, GraphQL, React, Golang.

# Experience

## Senior Application Developer - Nike Valiant Labs

01/2018 - 07/2019

Work with many teams at Nike Valiant Labs to help bringing their new ideas to life. Architect and implement applications for products quickly. Collaborate and mentor other junior developers.

# UI Developer II, Healthsparq - Cambia Health Solutions 12/2016 - 01/2018

Work with talented Healsparq team to build products that reinvent healthcare industries for a better and transparent healthcare.

## Senior Front-end Developer, Seastar.io

03/2015 - 12/2016

Lead of front-end development to design and create intuitive web application for Seastar dashboard using EmberJS, D3.js, Go, Cassandra.

# Web Application Engineer, The Program PDX

10/2014 - 03/2015

Take technical ownership of projects and be responsible for architecting and developing complex digital solutions using full-stack development.

## Web Developer, Sincerely Truman (Epipheo)

08/2011 - 10/2014

Work with clients to develop complex websites and applications. Build highly customized Wordpress themes and Wordpress plugins.

# Labs Technician and Server Operations, Portland State University 06/2010 - 08/2012

Work with server operations team to mange Portland State datacenter. Support staffs and students at PSU for computer software and hardware.

# Education

BS. Computer Science, Portland State University 2009 - 2012

Advanced Computer Science Program, Vietnam National University 2007 - 2009

## Contact

 $\searrow$ 

khoa.pham@me.com

www.khoapham.me

Y

@pmkhoa
github.com/pmkhoa

## Tech Skills

#### Front-end

React, Redux, NextJS, EmberJS, GraphQL, Apollo, D3, ThreeJS, TweenMax.

## **Programming Languages**

Javascript, Go, PHP, Ruby, Java, HTML.

#### **Database**

Postgres, GraphQL, MySQL.

### **Frameworks**

Ember, Rails, ExpressJS, Wordpress, Go Web API.

### DevOps

AWS, Lamda, Linux Server, Docker, Serverless.

#### **Work Tools**

Vim, Tmux, Git, Sketch, Slack.

### UX

Photoshop, Sketch, sharp eyes for UI and UX design.

# Hobbies

Practice meditation

Learn latest technology

Cooking

Play lego with my kids